<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on Blog · Muhammad Fauzi Islami</title>
    <link>https://fauzislami.github.io/categories/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Blog · Muhammad Fauzi Islami</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 11:26:52 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://fauzislami.github.io/categories/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>K8S-thing: How Linux Namespace Plays a Role in Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://fauzislami.github.io/blog/k8s-thing-how-linux-namespace-Plays-a-role-in-Kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 11:26:52 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fauzislami.github.io/blog/k8s-thing-how-linux-namespace-Plays-a-role-in-Kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Linux Network Namespace Before we look into how Linux Network Namespace works in Kubernetes Pod, we need to know from the basic what it is and what the purpose of it. Network namespace in linux provides an isolated system resources associated with networking-related stuff within a single host such as IP (Internet Protocol) either it is IPv4 or IPv6, NAT rules, firewall rules, and routing table.
Let&amp;rsquo;s imagine you are a parent who have children and live in a house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highly Available Kubernetes Cluster Using HAproxy and Keepalived</title>
      <link>https://fauzislami.github.io/blog/2021/10/17/highly-available-kubernetes-cluster-with-haproxy-and-keepalived/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 10:16:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fauzislami.github.io/blog/2021/10/17/highly-available-kubernetes-cluster-with-haproxy-and-keepalived/</guid>
      <description>Kubernetes provides us a convenient way to make our application easier to maintain and more scalable. Since kubernetes is only an abstraction that runs on a set of machines and consists of many components, we have some work to do to keep our kubernetes cluster well-established and healthy, especially to make that cluster highly available. In this case, I use two HAproxy instances to balance the load over the network or we usually say that as load balancing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing K8S Secret Object Using SealedSecret</title>
      <link>https://fauzislami.github.io/blog/2021/09/26/secure-k8s-secret-object-using-sealedsecret/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 08:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fauzislami.github.io/blog/2021/09/26/secure-k8s-secret-object-using-sealedsecret/</guid>
      <description>Managing kubernetes manifest on Git or any other SCM is a common task nowadays. It makes life easier if we talk about continuous deployment. However, there is a manifest that should not be stored on SCM, it&amp;rsquo;s secret object. Secret object on Kubernetes was made to hide any sensitive data including user credentials and key. Unfortunately, secret object is not completely secure, it does not encrypt but only uses base64 encoding scheme to hide the data and it can be easily decoded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Mesh : Istio and Kiali Setup</title>
      <link>https://fauzislami.github.io/blog/2021/08/01/service-mesh-istio-and-kiali-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 12:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fauzislami.github.io/blog/2021/08/01/service-mesh-istio-and-kiali-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fauzislami.github.io/images/service-mesh-istio-kiali-setup/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Scratchpad&#34; title=&#34;Scratchpad&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the first time for me to learn what service mesh is, how it works, and how to start the lab to deep dive on this stuff. In this article, there will be some of my notes about how to install Istio and see the visualization of some microservices that will have been monitored by Istio and I’m going to write it up now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating K8S Cluster Installation with Kubespray</title>
      <link>https://fauzislami.github.io/blog/2021/01/18/automating-k8s-cluster-installation-with-kubespray/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 17:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://fauzislami.github.io/blog/2021/01/18/automating-k8s-cluster-installation-with-kubespray/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://fauzislami.github.io/images/automating-k8s-cluster-kubespray/pic-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;kubespray&#34; title=&#34;kubespray&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are various ways to perform a kubernetes installation. If you look at the environment in which kubernetes will be installed on, you have options that can be done, namely:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
